Alberto Aguilera Juárez

Date of birth: April 8th, 1988 Place of birth: Barcelona, Spain Phone Number: 075 9894 6479 E-mail: albertoaguileraj@gmail.com Webpage: https://www.albertoaj.com

Profile

I'm very passionate about programming, and I like to learn about every kind of technology because I believe it helps to think out of the box and get new ideas. However, I'm trying to learn and become an expert in test automation and web development.

Especially, I have a strong interest in:

- Test driven development and continuous integration.
- Design of web service architectures like SOAP, RESTful and others.
- Scripting languages like Python, Scala and Bash.
- Artificial intelligence, machine learning and algorithmics.

I like to try and contribute to other people's projects, even if it's only by reviewing code and giving my opinion on how it could be improved. I love to start new projects and see how these slowly grow. Sometimes, I also like to provide some of the code I write to the public, so I have my own space in GitHub, where I can do so: https://github.com/drimer

Professional experience

■ Geneity Ltd

 $Software\ Engineer$

03/2014 - current

- Develop automated processing for data coming from external feeds in order to track latest updates on sports events.
- Improve code quality and development process by introducing TDD in the company and help other developers write better unit tests.
- Add new functionalities to Geneity's base sportsbook, on a per-customer's requests demand as, for instance, every country has different laws involving sports betting.
- Actively involved with DevOps and Test Automation.

■ YouView TV Limited

Software Engineer

10/2012 - 03/2014

- Maintain a webpage that distributes tests among different machines and set-top-boxes, runs them an gathers results and logs, offering a user-friendly UI. Using: Python, Flask, HTML/CSS, JavaScript.
- Extend test coverage of the test suite, maintain the existing tests analasing false negatives in the results and automate classification of bugs detected. Using: Python and Bash.
- Write Python tools and libraries to make the tests readable by other teams composed by non-programmers.
- Hunt for the reason behind existing bugs in the set-top-boxes by analysing logs (DBus, and home-made logging systems).
- Extend the open-source tool stb-tester in order to measure non-functional requirements on the set-topboxes.
- Analyse requirements of the test automation system so that even non IT specialized members at YouView can use it to run tests on the set-top-boxes.

• Ábaco Andaluza de Arte y Artesanía S.L.

Webmaster 11/2011 - 03/2012

- I did an internship in this company as web developer of libreriababilonia.com and abacoarte.com.
- I maintained both webpages following SEO specialists' demands for positioning and adding new features. Using: Python, Django, HTML/CSS, PHP, Prestashop.
- Dinamizador

 Andalucía Compromiso Digital (Cruz Roja)

Jaén, España 11/2008-10/2009

Valencia, España

07/2007

• Volunteers in ACD are to bring people near new technologies. Their main purpose is to let everyone use any technological device, regardless their age, ethnicity or special conditions.

Skills

■ Python: Advanced

■ **Git:** Advanced

Campus Party

Volunteer

Linux: AdvancedBash: Advanced

Javascript: Intermediate HTML/CSS: Intermediate

ANSI C: Intermediate
C++: Intermediate
PL/SQL: Intermediate

Test development: I have experience in automating tests, using Jenkins as a CI tool, writing libraries and tools to test the UI of set-top-boxes, as well as identifying issues at lower levels by analysig logs i.e. (dbus, serial), reporting and keeping track of them using JIRA.

Desktop development: I have used Java several times, as well as C++ with Qt, and Python with pyGtk.

Web development: I have written webpages using Flask (Python), HTML/CSS and jQuery.

Operating Systems: I'm a casual user of Windows, and a daily user of Linux. I am used to dealing with all sorts of problems by using the Linux shell and all the low level tools provided by the operating system.

Projects

Even though these are just tiny projects I've written, and most of them aren't even near to be halfway through, this is a list with the ones I've enjoyed developing the most:

NetControl: allows a user to allow or deny network operations performed from every terminal in his own LAN network. Technologies used: Linux, Python, Bash, iptables and Qt.

QtPaint: small example of a Paint written in C++ using Qt. Technologies used: Linux, C++ and Qt.

albertoaj_com: the source code of my personal webpage. Technologies used: Python, Flask, HTML and JavaScript.

Education

■ Introduction to Project Management
City University of London

2013

■ Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science University of Granada

2009 - 2012

■ Introduction to Artificial Intelligence Stanford University

Online Course 2012

■ Introduction to Robotics University of Jaén

03/2006

Languages

Spanish: NativeCatalan: Native

■ English: Certificate of Advanced English (Cambridge ESOL)

Availability

I have driving license and to a certain extent, moving around within the city and its sorroundings would be no problem for me.